["Deck the Halls" playing]
[播放“Deck the Halls”]
♪ ♪
♪♪
Ta da!
哒哒！
This gift is for Santa Claus.
这份礼物是送给圣诞老人的。
Even Santa deserves
a gift, right Gary?
即使是圣诞老人也值得
一份礼物，对吧加里？
[meows]
[喵喵]
♪ Santa Claus, Santa Claus ♪
♪ 圣诞老人，圣诞老人 ♪
♪ Santa's on his way ♪
♪ 圣诞老人正在赶来的路上 ♪
♪ I'm giving him a present ♪
♪ 我要送他一份礼物 ♪
♪ That he'll take back
on his sleigh ♪
♪ 他会收回的
在他的雪橇上♪
Yay! [vocalizing]
耶！ [发声]
Ho, ho, ho!
嗬，嗬，嗬！
Hmm...
唔...
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Oh, yeah, I forgot.
哦，是的，我忘了。
Ho, ho, ho, shrink-o.
嗬，嗬，嗬，收缩-o。
[vocalizing "Jingle Bells"]
[发出“铃儿响叮当”的声音]
Ho, ho, ho!
嗬，嗬，嗬！
narrator: Seven months later.
旁白：七个月后。
Excuse me, Mr. Sofa.
对不起，沙发先生。
Ha, look at that, Gary.
哈，看看那个，加里。
It's the present I left
for Santa last Christmas.
这是我留下的礼物
去年圣诞节给圣诞老人。
Isn't that nice?
这不是很好吗？
The present I left for Santa
last Christmas!
我留给圣诞老人的礼物
去年圣诞节！
He never got it.
他从来没有得到过。
Oh, this is the worst disaster
that's ever happened.
噢，这是最严重的灾难
这种事曾经发生过。
My present to Santa
is 212 days late.
我给圣诞老人的礼物
晚了212天。
Late, it's a tragedy.
来晚了，悲剧了。
My joyful carefree world
is growing dark and dreary.
我的快乐无忧无虑的世界
天色越来越暗，越来越沉闷。
I can't go on.
我无法继续下去了。
No, I'll go on.
不，我会继续。
But I can't go on!
但我不能继续下去了！
Whoo-hoo! [whistles]
呼呼！ [口哨声]
Whoo-hoo! Five stars.
呼呼！五颗星。
Patrick, I wasn't acting.
帕特里克，我没有演戏。
Santa never got
his Christmas present.
圣诞老人从未得到过
他的圣诞礼物。
So why not just
deliver it to him?
那么为什么不只是
送给他？
Why not just deliver it to him?
为什么不直接送给他呢？
[chuckles]
That's a dumb idea.
[笑声]
这是一个愚蠢的想法。
I'm in!
- Great!
我进来了！
- 伟大的！
But how will we get there?
We can't walk that far.
但我们怎样才能到达那里呢？
我们走不了那么远。
Oh, we can push
and shove each other.
哦，我们可以推动
并互相推搡。
Great idea!
好主意！
We can't let it be
one more day late.
我们不能让它这样
又晚了一天。
Okay, me first.
好吧，我先。
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
My turn!
轮到我了！
- What the...
- Merry Christmas.
- 什么...
- 圣诞快乐。
Um, it's July?
嗯，现在是七月吗？
Ah, it's a good day to be bad.
啊，今天是坏事的好日子。
[laughing]
[笑]
[laughs]
Uh, SpongeBob?
You got a booger.
呃，海绵宝宝？
你有鼻屎。
Oh!
哦！
Don't worry,
that's what friends are for.
别担心，
这就是朋友的目的。
Blow.
吹。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Eww!
哇！
It's the ugliest booger
I've ever seen.
这是最丑的鼻屎
我曾经见过。
Can't you screwballs
walk without falling?
你不能搞鬼吗
走路不摔倒？
Sorry Plankton.
对不起，浮游生物。
We're pushing
and shoving ourselves
我们正在推动
并推挤我们自己
all the way to the North Pole.
一直到北极。
I have to give Santa
his Christmas present.
我必须给圣诞老人
他的圣诞礼物。
Santa? I hate that guy.
圣诞老人？我讨厌那个家伙。
He's had me on a naughty list
ever since I got this tattoo.
他把我列入了淘气名单
自从我有了这个纹身。
both: Born to be naughty?
两人：天生顽皮？
Whoo! Wait a minute.
呼！等一下。
If I can
break into Santa's lair,
如果我可以的话
闯入圣诞老人的巢穴，
hack his mainframe,
change my status
破解他的主机，
改变我的状态
from naughty to nice,
从调皮到乖巧，
I could ask for
the Krabby Patty secret formula
我可以要求
蟹黄派的秘密配方
and he'd have to give it to me.
他必须把它给我。
I'm coming with you.
我跟你一起去。
- Pushed or shoved?
- Shrimp that!
- 推还是推？
- 虾那个！
We are going in style, babies.
我们将以时尚的方式出发，宝贝们。
[engine rumbling]
[发动机轰鸣]
both: Whoa!
两人：哇！
I built it to fly
and run over bodies
我建造它是为了飞翔
并碾过尸体
during the zombie apocalypse,
在僵尸大灾难期间，
but it'll work on snow too.
但它也适用于雪。
We'll take the Pacific
to the Arctic,
我们将占领太平洋
到北极，
then over ice and snow
to the North Pole.
然后越过冰雪
到北极。
Easy-peasy, Santa-squeezy.
[chuckles]
轻松，圣诞老人。
[笑声]
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
Seat belts.
安全带。
Of course, safety first.
当然，安全第一。
All secured, Captain Plankton.
一切都安全了，浮游生物船长。
All secured.
全部安全。
[groans] I'm already
regretting this trip.
[呻吟]我已经
后悔这次旅行。
- Whee! [laughs]
- Ya-hoo!
- 呼！ [笑]
- 雅虎！
[vocalizing]
[发声]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[groans]
[呻吟]
We did it!
我们做到了！
Oh, look at those
tiny little fish.
哦，看看那些
小鱼。
both: Hi.
两人：嗨。
Hey, get back to your seats!
嘿，回到座位上吧！
The seat belt sign is off.
安全带指示灯熄灭。
[groans]
[呻吟]
[gasps]
[喘气]
The visitors, they're here!
访客，他们来了！
He seemed happy to see us.
他似乎很高兴见到我们。
Oh!
哦！
Ah!
- Whoa, a flying lawn chair.
啊!
- 哇，一把会飞的草坪椅。
- Hey!
- Give me that.
- 嘿！
- 给我那个。
What's in this box anyway?
- It's a surprise.
这个盒子里到底装着什么？
- 这是一个惊喜。
I hope it's a stink bomb
我希望这是一颗臭弹
for that
pot-bellied jingle joker.
为此
大腹便便的小丑。
Santa is not pot-bellied.
圣诞老人可不是大腹便便的。
He just suffers
from seasonal bloating.
他只是受苦
来自季节性腹胀。
Right.
正确的。
I'm going to sleep.
我要去睡觉。
But who will fly this thing?
但谁会驾驶这个东西呢？
I put it on automatic pilot.
我把它调到自动驾驶仪上。
You and that pink moron
can sleep on the floor.
你和那个粉红白痴
可以睡在地板上。
[claps]
[鼓掌]
[groans]
[呻吟]
Hey, what are you
imbeciles doing?
嘿，你是什么
蠢货在做什么？
We found the North Pole.
我们找到了北极。
It was way closer than you said.
比你说的要近得多。
North Pole?
北极？
Impossible.
不可能的。
How long was I asleep?
我睡了多久？
Funny how the ground
keeps getting closer.
有趣的是地面如何
越来越近。
Welcome to
Christmas Land Theme Park.
欢迎来到
圣诞乐园主题公园。
Where every day is Christmas.
每天都是圣诞节。
Hey, get out of my seat.
嘿，离开我的座位。
[dinging]
[叮叮]
The seat belt sign is on.
安全带标志亮起。
Cabin crew, prepare for landing.
机组人员，准备着陆。
Do you actually
know how to land?
你实际上吗
知道如何着陆吗？
I know how to crash land.
我知道如何迫降。
My seat belt!
我的安全带！
both: The North Pole!
两者：北极！
We made it!
我们成功了！
[groaning]
[呻吟]
Huh? Look what you two
broken brain buffoons did!
啊？看看你们两个
脑子坏了的小丑干的！
You completely destroyed
the navigation system.
你彻底摧毁了
导航系统。
You're welcome.
不客气。
Don't be mad, Plankton.
We're here.
别生气，浮游生物。
我们到了。
Look at all this.
看看这一切。
[both giggling]
[两人都咯咯笑]
Hmm.
唔。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
Ooh, Santa's elves.
哦，圣诞老人的精灵们。
[both gasp]
- Santa's reindeer!
[两人都喘气]
- 圣诞老人的驯鹿！
both: This is amazing!
两人：这太棒了！
Something's wrong here.
这里出了点问题。
It isn't even cold.
And look at this smog.
甚至不冷。
看看这烟雾。
- It's snow and smog?
- It's "snog."
- 有雪和烟雾吗？
- 这是“接吻”。
[both giggling]
[两人都咯咯笑]
[sighs]
[叹气]
Santa's workshop!
圣诞老人的工作坊！
all: ♪ Making toys,
work, work, work ♪
全部：♪ 制作玩具，
工作、工作、工作♪
♪ Making toys,
work, work, work ♪
♪ 制作玩具，
工作、工作、工作♪
Hello, Santa's elves,
I'm SpongeBob. Merry Christmas.
你好，圣诞老人的小精灵们，
我是海绵宝宝。圣诞快乐。
[voice distorted]
Make, work... make, work...
[声音扭曲]
制作，工作...制作，工作...
Looks like Santa's
gone all in for automation.
看起来像圣诞老人
全力以赴实现自动化。
Hey guys, look.
嘿伙计们，看。
It says, [gasps]
"meet Santa Claus!"
它说，[喘气]
“来见见圣诞老人吧！”
Come on, guys! [giggles]
- Let's meet Santa!
来吧，伙计们！ [咯咯笑]
- 让我们来见见圣诞老人吧！
[muttering]
[嘀咕]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
We're finally here,
little present.
我们终于来了，
小礼物。
Guys, I hate to say this,
but this place is a sham.
伙计们，我讨厌这样说，
但这个地方是一个骗局。
I don't know why,
but we're being tricked.
我不知道为什么，
但我们被欺骗了。
Oh, Plankton,
Christmas is about believing.
哦，浮游生物，
圣诞节是关于相信的。
Yeah, Christmas
is about bleeding, man.
是的，圣诞节
是关于流血的，伙计。
[both gasp]
[两人都喘气]
[snoring]
[打鼾]
[both giggling]
[两人都咯咯笑]
I wouldn't believe it if I
didn't see it with my own eye.
我不会相信如果我
没有亲眼所见。
The bearded weirdo in the flesh.
肉体中的大胡子怪人。
[muttering]
[嘀咕]
What would you like
for Christmas?
你想要什么
圣诞节？
[both speaking at once]
[两人同时发言]
Pipe down, children.
放下心来，孩子们。
What the...
什么...
[gasps]
[喘气]
SpongeBob SquarePants?
海绵宝宝？
Hi, Santa.
嗨，圣诞老人。
Did you know
that I'm your biggest fan?
你知道吗
我是你最大的粉丝？
Oh, that's very sweet
of you Santa
哦，这很甜蜜
你圣诞老人
but actually Patchy the Pirate
is my biggest fan.
但实际上海盗帕奇
是我最大的粉丝。
Ho, ho, ho!
嗬，嗬，嗬！
Ahoy, SpongeBob and Patrick!
嘿，海绵宝宝和帕特里克！
It's me, Patchy the Pirate.
是我，海盗帕奇。
Patchy the Pirate?
海盗帕奇？
You're Santa?
你是圣诞老人吗？
No, I just play Santa here
in Christmas Land Theme Park.
不，我只是在这里扮演圣诞老人
在圣诞乐园主题公园。
It's me side-hustle.
这是我的副业。
I knew this wasn't
the North Pole.
我知道这不是
北极。
North Pole?
No, man, this be Encino.
北极？
不，伙计，这是恩西诺。
You're almost 4,000 miles
from the North Pole.
您已行驶近 4,000 英里
来自北极。
[growls]
[咆哮]
I'm gonna destroy you two!
我要毁了你们两个！
4,000 miles?
4,000 英里？
Oh, if only our GPS
wasn't busted.
哦，如果只有我们的 GPS 就好了
没有被抓。
Ooh, I can help
with global positioning.
哦，我可以帮忙
具有全球定位。
Way before GPS,
远早于 GPS，
pirates used
these things called maps.
海盗使用
这些东西叫做地图。
Oh, and you'll need
a compass too.
哦，你需要
还有指南针。
[squawks] Happy holidays.
[尖叫]节日快乐。
[grunts]
[both laugh]
[咕哝]
[两人都笑了]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Polly want a smacker?
波莉想要一个咂嘴吗？
Well, thanks, Patchy.
Guess we'll be on our way.
好吧，谢谢，帕奇。
猜猜我们会上路的。
Goodbye! Good luck.
再见！祝你好运。
If you see Santy Claus,
tell him I want a new parrot.
如果你看到圣诞老人，
告诉他我想要一只新鹦鹉。
- [squawks]
- Hey!
- [嘎嘎声]
- 嘿！
- And I want a new pirate.
- Ow!
- 我想要一个新海盗。
- 噢！
Woah!
哇！
Wait, where are we?
等等，我们在哪里？
[all scream]
[全部尖叫]
all: Whoa!
所有人：哇！
[shivering] S-S-Santa's
workshop, dead ahead.
[颤抖]S-S-圣诞老人的
车间，正前方。
[shivering] J-j-just in time.
I'm f-f-freezing.
[发抖] J-J-来得正是时候。
我快冻僵了。
Are we there yet?
我们到了吗？
How you doing with
that Plankton pop?
你怎么样
浮游生物流行音乐？
I can't wait to
get to the chewy middle.
我等不及了
到达有嚼劲的中间。
[groaning]
[呻吟]
Hey Patrick, where's Plankton?
嘿帕特里克，浮游生物在哪里？
I don't know.
我不知道。
[gasps]
[喘气]
[groans]
[呻吟]
Eat a breath mint, trench mouth.
吃一口薄荷，沟口。
All right, here it goes.
好吧，就这样吧。
Huh?
啊？
Aw, you guys look great!
噢，你们看起来棒极了！
I like your spaceman helmets.
我喜欢你的太空人头盔。
But it's not Halloween
for another three months.
但这不是万圣节
再过三个月。
We're not here for Halloween,
we're here for Santa.
我们不是来过万圣节的
我们是来迎接圣诞老人的。
I've got my own agenda
我有自己的议程
so this is
where we part company.
所以这是
我们分手的地方。
Oh, sorry, Santa's not home.
哦，抱歉，圣诞老人不在家。
He's in Aruba with the Missus.
他和太太在阿鲁巴岛。
But... here you go anyway.
但是……无论如何，你还是走吧。
But... but...
但是……但是……
Happy Halloween!
万圣节快乐！
[upbeat rockabilly music]
[欢快的摇滚音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
both: Whoa!
两人：哇！
[gasps]
[喘气]
Ah! Eh, ah!
啊!诶诶诶！
Hey, that's Plankton.
He's inside.
嘿，那是浮游生物。
他在里面。
[knocking]
- Eh?
[敲门声]
- 呃？
Bleh. Jeez.
布莱赫。天啊。
I have to get
Santa's present under his tree.
我必须得到
圣诞老人的礼物在他的树下。
We've got to get inside.
我们必须进去。
Ah! I'm on it.
啊!我正在做。
Hmm, I know!
嗯，我知道！
We'll go in Santa style.
Down the chimney.
我们将以圣诞老人的方式去。
顺着烟囱下去。
Oh, fine, we'll go
with your idea.
哦，好吧，我们这就走
与你的想法。
Hmm, now where in Kris Kringle
嗯，现在在 Kris Kringle 的哪里
is Santa's mainframe?
是圣诞老人的主机吗？
[hard rock music]
[硬摇滚音乐]
♪ ♪
♪♪
No mainframe,
没有主机，
just lame brains.
只是个蹩脚的大脑。
Yo, where do you think
you're going?
哟，你觉得哪里
你要去吗？
[high-pitched] Who, me?
I'm just a little elf!
[高声调] 谁，我？
我只是一个小精灵！
[sniffs]
You don't smell like no elf.
[嗅嗅]
你闻起来不像精灵。
Oh, yeah?
What's it to you, you moose?
哦，是吗？
你这驼鹿，关你什么事？
[snorts]
[哼哼]
Hey! Dasher, Dancer, Prancer,
嘿！冲刺者、舞者、舞者、
Vixen, Comet, Cupid,
Donner, Blitzen!
泼妇、彗星、丘比特、
唐纳，闪电战！
[all growling]
[全都咆哮]
Well, looks like we got
a whole Christmas special here.
嗯，看起来我们得到了
这里有整个圣诞节的特别节目。
Ready for some reindeer games?
准备好玩一些驯鹿游戏了吗？
Eh, peace on earth?
呃，地球和平吗？
Whoa! Oof, oof, ow!
哇！噢，噢，噢！
That better be mud
on your hooves.
最好是泥
在你的蹄子上。
[both grunt]
[两人咕哝]
[gasps] That's it!
[喘气]就是这样！
Santa's Christmas tree.
圣诞老人的圣诞树。
[both giggle]
[两人都咯咯笑]
[alarm blaring]
[警报声]
There they are!
It's the trick-or-treaters!
他们在那里！
这就是“不给糖就捣蛋”的人！
- Toy thieves!
- Christmas crooks!
- 玩具小偷！
- 圣诞骗子！
Get 'em!
抓住他们！
SpongeBob, what do we do?
海绵宝宝，我们该怎么办？
Climb!
爬！
They're going up the tree!
他们要上树了！
Don't let 'em get away.
别让他们跑了。
[alarm blaring]
[警报声]
We better check that alarm!
我们最好检查一下警报！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
I wore you down, didn't I?
我让你疲惫不堪，不是吗？
You meat head cari-boobs.
你这个肉头加勒比胸部。
Toy thieves!
玩具小偷！
Yo, elves!
哟，精灵们！
What the Father Christmas
is going on here?
什么是圣诞老人
这是怎么回事？
We got this under control.
Go back to your stables.
我们已经控制住了这一切。
回到你的马厩去吧。
Oh!
Not cool elf bros.
哦！
不是很酷的精灵兄弟。
Ow! Oof!
噢！钱币！
[shouts]
[喊叫]
Whoa!
哇！
Hmm? Oof!
唔？钱币！
[laughs]
[笑]
Hey! Not funny.
嘿！不好笑。
Ah!
啊!
Whoa, whoa!
哇哦！
[all groan]
[全都呻吟]
[train whistle blows]
[火车鸣笛]
Oh, no, Patrick.
哦，不，帕特里克。
It looks like I have sowed
the seeds of discontent
看来我已经播种了
不满的种子
in the house of Santa.
在圣诞老人的家里。
Patrick? Huh?
帕特里克？啊？
Candy cane... oh!
拐杖糖...哦！
[gasps]
[喘气]
Oh!
哦！
[cackles]
[咯咯笑]
Oh! [groans]
哦！ [呻吟]
[gasps] Santa's mainframe.
I found it!
[喘气]圣诞老人的主机。
我找到了！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Thanks to those two idiots
causing a distraction,
感谢那两个白痴
造成分心，
I did it.
My name is the nice list.
我做到了。
我的名字是好名单。
Now I just gotta be good
for the next few months.
现在我只需要做个好人
在接下来的几个月里。
How hard could that be?
那有多难？
He-he-he... wah!
嘿嘿嘿……哇！
Oh! What the ho, ho, ho
is going on here?
哦！什么嗬嗬嗬
这是怎么回事？
I was kicking back with
the Missus in the Caribbean
我正在反击
加勒比海的太太
when my silent alarm went off.
当我的无声闹钟响起时。
- [chuckles] Huh?
- Hi, Santa.
- [笑] 嗯？
- 嗨，圣诞老人。
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
Ho, ho, I should've known!
嗬嗬，我早该知道的！
You're a menace.
你是一个威胁。
[laughs]
[笑]
All I wanted to do
was leave you this present
我想做的一切
给你留下了这个礼物
that you didn't get
last Christmas.
你没有得到的
去年圣诞节。
213 days late. Sorry!
晚了213天。对不起！
A present is never too late.
礼物永远不会太晚。
Oh, how sweet.
噢，多么甜蜜啊。
Not even the elves or reindeer
get me presents.
甚至连精灵或驯鹿也没有
给我送礼物。
- Um...
- Ah...
- 嗯...
- 啊...
Thank you, SpongeBob.
谢谢你，海绵宝宝。
Should I open it now?
- Uh-huh, uh-huh!
我现在应该打开它吗？
- 嗯嗯，嗯嗯！
[all gasp]
[全都喘气]
It's one of a kind.
这是独一无二的。
[gasps]
[喘气]
The Krabby Patty secret formula?
蟹黄饼的秘密配方？
He's giving it to Santa Claus!
他要把它送给圣诞老人！
Forget the list,
the formula's right here.
忘记清单了，
公式就在这里。
I could have it now!
我现在就可以拥有它！
[laughing]
[笑]
Huh?
啊？
[cackling]
[咯咯笑]
Ah!
啊!
Huh? Plankton?
啊？浮游生物？
You're being naughty.
你很顽皮。
Santa, I was born to be naughty.
圣诞老人，我生来就是淘气的。
- Wha... hmm.
- Hmm.
- 什...嗯。
- 唔。
Yeah. [chuckles]
是的。 [笑声]
[mutters]
[嘀咕]
Um, yeah...
嗯，是的...
you can have this back.
你可以把这个拿回来。
My bad, heh.
I mean, good... my good.
我的不好，呵呵。
我的意思是，好……我的好。
I'm being nice, not naughty.
我性格很好，不淘气。
Well, read it out loud.
好吧，大声读出来。
Uh, that's okay.
呃，没关系。
Go on, read it.
继续，读吧。
all: Read it!
全体：读吧！
"Dear Santa,
“亲爱的圣诞老人，
"there isn't
a present big enough
“没有
足够大的礼物
"to express how much joy
you've brought
”来表达多少喜悦
你带来了
"to all the children and
sea creatures of the world.
“致所有的孩子们和
世界上的海洋生物。
"So this is just
a simple thank you note.
“所以这只是
一封简单的感谢信。
"Thank you.
“谢谢。
Signed, with love,
your pal SpongeBob."
带着爱意签名，
你的朋友海绵宝宝。”
[all cooing]
[全都咕咕叫]
You got a typo here.
你这里有一个错字。
Oh, how touching.
哦，多么感人啊。
This is beautiful.
这很漂亮。
Thank you, SpongeBob.
谢谢你，海绵宝宝。
I wouldn't have made it here
without the help of Plankton.
我不会做到这里
没有浮游生物的帮助。
He's really not that naughty.
他其实没那么调皮。
And of course,
my best friend Patrick.
当然，
我最好的朋友帕特里克。
Patrick?
帕特里克？
Happy holidays to me!
祝我节日快乐！
narrator: The next Christmas.
旁白：下一个圣诞节。
Aww, here you go!
哇哦，给你！
[chuckles]
Happy holidays, everybody.
[笑声]
大家节日快乐。
Sheldon.
谢尔顿。
Lump of coal.
煤块。
Merry Christmas, Plankton.
圣诞快乐，浮游生物。
Another lump of coal no doubt.
毫无疑问又是一块煤。
What's this?
这是什么？
"Merry Christmas to Plankton!
“祝浮游生物圣诞快乐！
One day you will
destroy us all."
有一天你会
毁灭我们所有人。”
Yes, I will, SpongeBob.
是的，我会的，海绵宝宝。
Yes, I will. [cackles]
是的，我会。 [咯咯笑]
Destroy!
破坏！
[roars]
[怒吼]
Ho, ho, ho! [cackles]
[all screaming]
嗬，嗬，嗬！ [咯咯笑]
[全都尖叫]